# **Lily Chen**

# **Software Engineer/Web Developer**

Full stack software engineer with an emphasis in creating visually appealing, user-friendly experiences. Strong skills in different front-end and back-end languages, frameworks, and databases including React, Express, Node.js, and MongoDB. Passionate about solving complex problems and focusing on the small details to ensure optimal user experience.

chenlily1998@gmail.com (917) 916-8039 Brooklyn, NY Portfolio LinkedIn Github

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **General Assembly**

Software Engineering Fellow

Remote | Jan 2022 - Apr 2022

 Skills: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Python, Git, GitHub

## Academic Success and Tutoring Center

Statistics Tutor

New York, NY | Sep 2018 - Dec 2019

- Provide private instruction to individual or small groups of students to improve academic performance and prepare for academic tests
- Teach students study skills, note-taking skills, and test-taking strategies
- Review class material with students by discussing text, working solutions to problems, or reviewing worksheets or other assignment

#### **Fisher Brothers**

**Building Office Intern** 

New York, New York | Jun 2018 - Aug 2019

- Perform general office duties, such as ordering supplies, maintain records on management database systems, and perform basic bookkeeping work
- Answer phone calls and direct calls to appropriate parties or take messages
- Prepare invoices, reports, letters, financial statements, and other documents using word processing, spreadsheet, and database software

#### **PROJECTS**

#### ChordStrike

Jan 2022

• An embedded Javascript application that stores information about your favorite songs, generates playlists of your desired length, and also displays the corresponding music videos. Built with EJS, Express, Node.js and MongoDB.

#### **Seoul Sisters**

Feb 2022

 An e-commerce React application displaying various Asian grocery projects. Visitors can browse products and leave reviews while site administrators can add/edit/delete products. Built with React, Express, Node.js and MongoDB.

#### Mission Atom

March 2022

 A space-themed React application where users can browse imaginary planets to potentially travel to. Users can also browse space related products to accompany their trip. Built with Typescript, React, Express, Node.js and MongoDB.

#### **SKILLS**

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- React
- MongoDB
- Python
- Django
- Express
- Node.js
- PostgreSQL
- jQuery
- Git
- GitHub

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Arts
Psychology
Stony Brook University
2016 - 2020